Gilmore.
Corn Syrup Droughts,
Bandwidth Riots
outlive them
make it
Columbus is the
fastest-growing city on Earth.
Halliday and Morrow
started Gregarious Games.
bummer
when you're running on
an omnidirectional treadmill
with quadraphonic,
pressure-sensitive underlay.
Surf a 50-foot monster wave
in Hawaii.
ski
down the pyramids.
Mount Everest
Check out this place.
It's a casino the size of a planet.
go in there
a different species,
live-action
It's all your call.
feel like
changing it.
Sector 12. Planet Doom.
and a pretty great place
to pick up coin.
Figures Aech would be there.
He's my best friend, period.
- What's up?
- Hey, what up, Z?
Next race is in 20 minutes,
and I can't do the late one.
What the hell are you up to?
Man, gettin' my kills on, bro.
Daito?
Sho.
This an artifact hunt?
Yup. Gregarious 120.
Turn into any giant robot
for two minutes. That's rad.
made sure
the OASIS was littered
with enough
randomly powerful stuff
that anyone could win
if they had the skills.
Death matches and artifact hunts
are a good way to coin-snatch,
Everything you've
ever worked for.
10 minutes
until the race starts.
brainchild
out of the picture
worshiped him
If you all wanna reach
under your seats,
But we're gonna... we're each
gonna bring you one now.
And what he left behind
Before I died, I created what we
in the biz call an "Easter egg."
I've hidden somewhere
inside the OASIS
will inherit my stock
in Gregarious Games,
currently valued in excess
of half a million do...
Uh, half a trillion
dollars' worth,
Anorak the All-Knowing,
test for worthy traits
revealing three hidden keys
to three magic gates.
And those with the skill
to survive these straits
will reach the end,
where the prize awaits.
Off you go, keys.
The keys aren't just laying
around under a rock somewhere.
I suppose you could say
they're invisible,
hidden in a dark room
that's at the center of a maze
Let the hunt
for Easter egg
begin.
The challenge
is to find three keys,
but in five years,
no one has even gotten one key.
And the big scoreboard?
Some long-forgotten gunter
cracked the first clue
and found the first challenge.
Then, this portal appeared.
that was so hard,
no one had ever finished it.
The only ones still trying are the gunters,
as in "egg hunters,"
the Sixers.
IOI...
...Innovative
Online Industries.
They're the second-largest
company in the world
with designs
on becoming the first.
Which is why they're putting
everything they got
into winning contest.
Buckle up!
Sit in!
We call 'em "Sixers"
'cause that's the company rule.
No name, just numbers.
They have a support team
made up of scholars.
Like me, they spend all their
time studying pop culture
was obsessed with,
trying to find clues
to solve the contest.
They're just following
the orders of the head of IOI,
this dickweed
named Nolan Sorrento.
How'd you get here before me?
Well, I didn't make a pit stop
at the hair salon.
- What up, Z?
- What's up?
Saved you a spot.
Ugh. So you can skim coins
from crashed cars?
Oh, but you still had enough to pay
for that Something About Mary hairdo.
are you seeing this?
Yeah, I see it.
That's Kaneda's bike from Akira.
It's a licensed skin
over a standard frame.
No, not the bike.
Forget the bike.
The girl,
I think it's Art3mis.
The Sixer Fixer?
I've seen all her walk-throughs,
her Twitch streams.
It's her. It's definitely her.
You got it, you got it!
Balls.
She's not gonna make it.
Bail! Bail out!
Bail!
Where did you find
an Iron Giant?
- Find it? I'm building it.
- That's a commission.
Oh, yeah.
is top-rated on the mod boards.
Oh, hey, check this out!
Hey. Z, yo.
- The Galactica, of course.
- These are my babies, all right, man?
Sulaco, from Aliens.
Dude, how are you
showing off my shit?
Valley Forge, from Silent Running.
Oh, where's the Harkonnen Drop-Ship?
That thing is sick.
Folds space like a boss.
I mean, you can get from Incipio
to Arrakis in three seconds...
Fingers!
You'll have to excuse him.
He gets a little nervous
around pretty girls.
Yup. He's pretty great.
I assume you and Shoulder
Blades are clanned up.
Nah.
Oh, 'cause you're Parzival,
as in the knight who found
the Holy Grail by himself.
Goddess of the hunt.
Clans must be killing to sign you up.
GoldenEye.
- Playing as?
- Oddjob
Favorite game variant?
Game variant was "slappers only."
I know what "slappers only" means.
Racer?
Turbo. And his favorite food
was Hot Pockets.
Favorite restaurant
was Chuck E Cheese.
Song was Video Killed the
Radio Star by the Buggles.
Video Take on Me by A-ha.
"come away thinking"
"ingredients on the back of a chewing-gum wrapper
Lex Luthor.
Oh! I mean,
I've got tons of plans in the real world.
Now I know
why you stopped short.
No one ever makes it past Kong.
Well, then you know it can't be true.
hated making rules.
- No, I'm not!
takes over the world.
There you go.
Thanks for the fix-up, my man.
I'll wave to you
from the finish line, McFly.
Captain Big Mouth.
Where the hell are my gloves?
Shit. I gotta go.
ANNOUNCE X1.
When I'm after gold on Planet Doom,
I need every edge I can get.
Get ready for the feel,
the feel of real. X1.
The X1 is like wearing
a second skin.
A skin that kicks ass.
I zeroed out 'cause
of your broke-ass gloves.
Why don't you just respawn and
level up like everyone else?
I bought all these power-ups for
this challenge, and I lost it all.
That artifact
was gonna pay for the house!
Wait.
How much of our house money
did you spend on upgrades?
Well, all of it,
but I was gonna win.
That was our ticket
out of here.
You idiot.
No, but I only lost 'cause
of the bad gloves.
Our house! Our goddamn house!
My boys
were in that challenge.
You couldn't have beat them
in a bootsuit, you noob.
No, we are not
calling the cops.
Go to your room, Rick.
Aw, come on, Alice.
Why do you put up with this guy?
He's a shitshow.
I ought to kick the both of you out.
I swear to G-O-D, Wade Watts,
if I catch you
touching my stuff again,
My dad picked that name
alter ego,
like Peter Parker
or Bruce Banner.
But he died when I was a kid.
My mom, too,
and I ended up here,
living with Aunt Alice
and her endless string
of hard-loving losers.
Why is that line
sticking in my head?
Maybe it's 'cause,
and she's hot.
Maybe it's because
she called me out,
sitting here
in my tiny corner of nowhere,
protecting my small slice
of nothing.
Or maybe...
Maybe it's because
that line means something
The day the contest
was announced,
Journals appeared.
He told us to look in his brain.
This was the next best thing.
At first, it was jammed with
gunters looking for answers.
Now, the once-crowded halls
of memories
are left to people like me.
Oh, joy!
And how will you eat up
my valuable search time today?
Gregarious Games, 2029...
Office party.
Yes, you've only seen it a thousand times.
Each entry into Journals is meticulously assembled
from personal photographs,
home video recordings,
surveillance, and nanny cams.
All rendered into a three-dimensional
virtual experience.
archived
located on the mezzanine.
No weapons or mature-themed avatars
are permitted within the Journals.
Please enjoy your time with us,
and happy gunting!
I like cleaning up.
Okay, Jim,
I'm, uh... I'm going.
Everything changes, Jim.
Everything evolves.
Some things are perfect just
the way they arAsteroids.
People don't live inside
an Asteroids arcade cabinet.
I know that.
Yeah, well,
people are living inside the arcade we built.
- I built.
- Uh, well...
Right. Well,
I guess you can say whatever you want.
I don't really wanna
talk about it anymore.
No, of course
you don't wanna talk about it.
You're forcing me out.
Closer on.
Look, invention
comes with responsibilities
you didn't ask for.
All right,
if you make something people want or need
then it's up to you to set the limits.
You have to make some rules.
I don't wanna make
any more rules.
We created something beautiful,
Jim, but it's changed.
Okay? It's really
not a game anymore.
I liked how things were
when they were...
When it was a game.
And we're back to where we started.
But that's the point, isn't it?
Things move forward
whether you like it or not.
Fine.
Why can't we go backwards,
for once?
Really put the pedal to the metal,
you know?
Why can't we go backwards,
for once?
Backwards, really fast.
Fast as we can.
Really put the pedal to the metal,
you know?
Bill and Ted did it.
Nice racing, Padawan.
and how the hell is he winning?
Well, here's a better question.
Who cares?
contest is vitally important.
I mean, it's nothing less than a
war for control of the future.
He's not even clanned up.
He's alone. We have an army.
And yet,
he's got the first key.
Our stock dove 6% yesterday.
profits of 28%. F'Nale.
Debt Services dwarfs Hardware.
Now, you really wanna talk
to me about stock prices?
The shareholders
won't be happy.
but once we launch this little baby,
they're gonna flip.
We call this Pure O2.
This is the first
of our planned upgrades.
Once we can roll back some of
ad restrictions,
we estimate
we can sell up to 80%
inducing seizures, so picture this...
All of this implies
we win the contest.
Dude, you won the key
and 100,000 coins?
As soon as I took the key,
all the coins
just appeared in my account.
I'll tell you what,
I'm soiling my haptics right now.
What the hell's a Cataclyst?
A bomb. Kills every avatar
on a planet, even the owner.
Who'd want that?
Twenty-thou
for the holy hand grenade?
That's a steal!
Whoa! Zemeckis Cube!
X1 haptic bootsuit.
i-R0k
To be honest,
I have kind of a neck thing.
It's like a carpel-tunnel deal
but with your neck,
if that's even a thing.
So if you could just stand
to... to your right.
Thanks, it's the repetitive stress.
Oh.
Here he is.
The steampunk pirate king.
I knew him well.
There are only three things
in this world I hate,
steampunk, pirates,
and tabbouleh.
I mean,
why do they even have it?
Is there a reason
we're meeting here?
The Orb of Osuvox.
It creates an impenetrable magic
shield that can only be taken down
by a magic spell.
Now, I'm gonna need you
to keep this for now.
I'm gonna let you know
when I wanna use it.
Right now, though,
I have another job for you.
Ah.
Can you do that?
Well, he's a superstar.
He made it
through the first gate
and avatars are gonna be
on him like hoes on Santa.
You never lick.
You bite straight
to the chocolaty center
of the Tootsie Pop.
Remember that old commercial,
with the owl?
Three times my normal fee.
Done.
Wait, really?
I should have asked for five.
Is four still on the table?
There's five of us
on the big board now.
was next,
no surprise there.
She was on the track when I won.
She saw me going backwards.
a tip, made him promise not
to say anything, and then he won next.
I'm pretty sure
he bragged to our pal,
'cause he won right after.
He totally totaled his car,
got it
"A creator who hates
his own creation.
Retrace your steps, escape your past."
"A creator who hates
his own creation.
"A hidden key, a leap not taken.
Retrace your steps, escape your past.
"And the key of jade
will be yours at last."
"Escape your past."
What part of your past are you
trying to escape?
You're, like,
totally my hero!
Over here!
Dude, you're amazing!
Right here!
Let me get an autograph!
Watch it!
Oh, God.
Ugh.
Oh, God. Don't you get it?
have a disguise.
Okay, here.
Clark Kent glasses.
They hide your identity
without changing your look.
The way your inventory
bursts out when you die.
They didn't want
any more blood.
This is right before
the OASIS went live.
Six days prior.
December 2nd, 2025.
Check this out.
You know who that is?
started as an intern.
He claims he learned
at the feet of the master.
But ask Ogden?
You could have, like,
different tiers of accounts,
like a gold member.
A person could be
silver, platinum, bronze.
You know, depending on
what they paid.
You know, highest one maybe being
"Water" because "OASIS," right?
Hell of a latte.
Can you fast-forward to the
stuff about date?
What? actually went
on a date?
Kira, The Dark Crystal.
That's her gamer tag.
- Karen.
Yeah, okay? Karen Underwood.
No, no. Karen Underwood,
as in?
What'd you do?
Just once, years before they
were even married, but yeah.
And despite that,
and the fact that she died,
is only mentioned once in all of Journals.
It is. Look it up.
What we just saw is the only
time she's ever mentioned.
She was an important part
of both their lives.
That's her gamer tag.
purposely removed every
mention of her except for this one.
It's like, it was just
so painful for him
to have to see her face
or hear her name.
Well, he loved her.
He couldn't tell that to.
Oh, that's sad.
He should have told her how he felt.
Yeah, well,
he missed his chance.
Look.
I found the clue to the race
in the other scene, but...
I've always felt
that the biggest clue
to the contest
was hidden here.
Don't sweat it, Curator.
the Rosebud at the center of his story.
You know The Distracted Globe?
And I was starting to.
No. Have you considered that
could be using you?
Hey, dude, she's giving me a clue.
Maybe I'm the one using her.
Should I go more Thriller?
Punk?
Duran Duran.
Does it look like
I'm trying too hard?
You have a massive cyber crush
on this girl.
She's hacking your heart
to get to your head.
I got it!
- Buckaroo Banzai?
Really? You're gonna wear the
outfit from your favorite movie?
Z, you gotta be more careful
about who you meet in the OASIS.
gets me.
She'll get my outfit.
There's just this connection.
I mean, sometimes, we even...
who lives in his mama's
basement in suburban Detroit.
Chuck.
Come here, man.
Hey, can we get a photo?
- Thank you so much!
- Dude, you're my hero!
What a freak!
I thought he was kind of cute.
Are you gonna kill their avatars?
Zero them out?
They're both here
at The Distracted Globe.
The Distracted Globe
was one of the first clubs
But I double-checked
Right, and she was
a serious dancer.
Maybe he thought
he'd take her here,
As if that ever works.
But they never made it
past the first date.
Who hates his own creation.
And the club
is the thing he hates.
And "A hidden key,
a leap not taken"?
We're not clanning up
or anything.
What kind of haptics
you rockin'?
You got the gloves and full visor,
or a full body?
I got the X1 haptic bootsuit with
the microfiber crotch inlay.
My,
you did come prepared.
Maybe it'd be cool if we
met up in the real world.
No, you'd be disappointed.
or my real face.
Are you crazy?
You don't tell anyone who you are.
It's an ambush.
Did you hear what I said?
I said I'm in love with you.
Watch out!
Pull.
Head back!
Zemeckis Cube.
I'm doing this to stop IOI.
I'm talking about
real-world consequences.
People suffering.
- Actual life-and-death stuff.
- He borrowed gear.
- He built up debt.
He moved in with the promise of
working it off, but he never did.
IOI just raised
his living expenses,
then he got sick,
and he couldn't afford to get out.
which, if we're offering
constructive criticism,
was a lame idea and only
would've slowed him down.
Whereas my plan, which was cool
because I rock, actually worked.
He's still on the board.
But he won't be for long.
I did a search
for all the Wades
who had recently bought
an X1 bootsuit,
cross-referenced that with public records,
and voila,
which is French for...
"And then I found out."
Are you loyal, Ms. Zandor?
Well, when you're at war,
you need people
who are loyal to a fault.
People you can count on
to get things done.
I just get people arrested
for not paying their bills.
Yeah, 'cause there are some problems
that require a physical solution,
but there are other times,
particularly at war,
when you need
a different set of rules.
So, this is one of those conversations
that we're not really having.
Well, we've had these kind
of conversations before,
and look where you are now.
You got a seat on the board,
head of your own division,
The only question is,
how far are we willing to go to win it?
IOI Plaza.
You're a hologram in the real world.
That's a really cool rig.
Thank you.
It's a brand-new Habashaw, OIR 9400.
You know, if you came to work at IOI,
you'd get one of these.
You'd also get your own
penthouse apartment in Columbus
You want the ship
from Defender?
You know, the kind that can
just jump into hyperspace?
You want
the Millennium Falcon?
And if you do happen to find that Easter egg,
there's a bonus.
I can see you're using
emotion-suppressing software right now,
and why wouldn't you?
It's smart, not to show your hand.
Well, I don't know about that.
What, for the OASIS?
I guess if you're not
a John Hughes fan...
is convert all the schools
on Ludus to replicas
from The Breakfast Club
and Ferris Bueller.
No way. That's a great idea.
Ridgemont or Faber?
Fast Times at Ridgemont High,
not John Hughes.
Faber College from Animal House.
John Hughes didn't direct
Fast Times at Ridgemont High
or Animal House.
Ferris Bueller and The Breakfast Club,
they went to Shermer High School,
which is in Shermer, Illinois.
I know what you think.
You think
I'm a corporate asshole,
Man, that's not true.
You know, when I wanna blow off steam...
Drink Tab, play Robotron,
listen to Duran Duran.
I crack open a Tab.
I put on some Duran Duran.
I play Robotron.
It just seems like he
wouldn't want you winning it.
A fanboy knows a hater,
and I know you've got a whole
department of oologists in your ear.
Your board of directors,
you got them in the other ear?
Why don't you tell 'em this.
If they dump you,
I'll consider it.
Wow, you really
switched gears there.
From fairly reasonable
to maniacal overlord.
You should be grateful
You won't be around
to endure my maniacal reign.
I also know where you are.
Unit 56K, Columbus stacks.
You were last seen entering
your trailer three days ago.
in some ghetto trash
rat warren in Columbus?
This bootsuit's pretty awesome.
Thanks for that.
Rick! Rick, the place
is gonna blow!
- Put Alice on!
- Let me talk to him.
IOI came for me
in the real world.
They gotta be coming after you,
so wherever you are...
Sorry about the blindfold.
paranoid.
Showers are that way,
clean clothes, too.
Welcome to the rebellion,
We've been living this close
to each other the whole time?
For the record,
I've lived with it my whole life.
You don't have to pretend.
Why would that scare me?
- I just figured it out.
- Figured what out?
We've been thinking about it
too literally.
"The leap not taken,"
the leap didn't take,
is with.
Yeah, but... I mean,
he blamed her for breaking up.
The place where the leap
wasn't taken.
Where the date was.
Okay, so our options for that
week are The Fly remake.
Great flick,
terrible date movie.
Say Anything...
That would make sense.
We gotta remember the clue.
No side chitchat.
Absolutely positive.
Let's hope
you have the belly for it.
Yeah, there are so many keys
The Shining, though.
I had
Okay, so we got the key
from room 237,
the keys to the Snowcat,
or the keys they give Jack
at the beginning of the movie.
Well,
if it's "the leap not taken,"
maybe the key
isn't a key at all.
I know
where the Snowcat keys are!
I say we split up.
We get all the keys
and then we meet back
at the Torrances' apartment.
Little girls, y'all know
how to get out of here?
Oh, uh, hi, naked lady.
I'm sorry.
I didn't mean to interrupt,
uh, your bath time.
Uh, I know self-care
can be important.
Uh, but can you do me a favor and tell me,
where are all the exits?
Okay, am I being punked?
'Cause you're likin' me
a little way too much.
All right, you know what?
I'ma go with it.
Ahh!
Time's running out.
Yo, Z, is
pissed at me?
Dude, I'm pissed at you.
You've never seen The Shining, have you?
You know I hate scary movies!
Sweet!
We ain't got no business
goin' to room 237!
We should stay out!
Plus, there was this crazy,
naked zombie lady in there.
There are no zombies
The Shining.
Well, maybe it's not supposed
to be like the movie.
Hey, y'all.
"Escape your past."
"The leap not taken."
greatest fear
wasn't The Shining
His biggest fear
was kissing a girl.
That's the leap
he couldn't take.
The ballroom.
Zombies. Told you.
None of this
is in The Shining.
Z, look. That's the zombie-circle
level in Mayhem Mansion,
The whole Shining trivia
is just a diversion.
One minute left.
How do we get to her?
Care to dance?
Jade Key.
Imagine that.
One of our oologists saw them
enter the media library.
She cracked the clue.
Get her off me!
I know. I'll get back to you.
I got what you're looking for.
Freeze. This guy.
The one with the lame tattoo.
Run him through our database,
every IOI drone in Columbus.
Groceries are here.
All right. Gluten-O's...
"If you know
the answer ultimate,
"divide it
by the number magic,
"and what you need, want, and desire
will be found in the fortress tragic."
"Tragic," that's gotta be
referring to himself.
Because he was lonely.
He had no one to spend his
life with towards the end.
Yeah, that's true.
The contest has gotta be somehow
about connecting with someone.
Anyone.
He wants the person
who cares for the OASIS
to be connected
with the world.
That's what I think
he's trying to tell us.
It's exactly
why I think you'll win.
Really? You really think
I'm gonna win?
Do not move!
Target identified!
Freeze! Don't move!
- This leads right to the alley.
- You first.
I'm right behind you. Go now!
Come on!
the OASIS needs you.
- I'm gonna delay them.
- Wait!
No, no, no, wait! No, no, no!
Freeze, freeze, freeze!
Don't move!
Samantha Evelyn Cook.
IOI has purchased and consolidated
all of your outstanding debt,
currently in excess
of 23,000 credits.
You will be remanded to the
nearest IOI loyalty center
until your debt
is paid in full,
including any interest,
processing,
or late fees
you incur henceforth.
Does anybody have eyes?
Check down the next street!
- "First to the key."
- "First to the egg."
Wait, what?
"Never trust someone you meet
in the OASIS."
"She might be a 300-pound dude
named Chuck..."
"Who lives in his mama's
basement in suburban Detroit."
Helen. My dad called me "H."
It kinda stuck. Let's go!
That thing's IDing my van.
Come on. They've spotted us.
My real name is Toshiro.
Samantha got us a message.
She told us to meet you here.
Samantha,
they took her to the...
The loyalty center, I know.
Look, in other awesome news,
the Sixers found the third challenge.
- What?
- Just come on, get in!
How did IOI find
the third challenge so fast?
IOI cracked the first
three lines of the clue,
so they knew it was sector 14
but they couldn't figure out
"the fortress tragic."
So they sent every guide
they had into that sector
until they found
the right fortress.
His real name is Xo.
But everyone else calls me Sho,
no big deal.
Sho, you're the world's most
badass 11-year-old ever.
We have to go save Samantha.
Well, we can't just
go through the doors of IOI.
Look, I've been thinkin' about it.
I got a better plan.
rig
Let's go after the man himself and
make him give back to us.
But first,
I have to know exactly,
how much about rig
do you remember?
Maintenance,
report to loyalty pod 31-B.
Security, please report
to section 97 for escort.
Newbie
Lay those charges
every six feet.
Keep it moving!
Hey, you!
Those are explosives!
IOI will not reimburse
any lost coin if you zero out.
Keep it moving!
So what is this challenge,
some sort of video game thing?
An Atari 2600, sir.
And every game ever made for it,
thousands of possibilities.
Come up!
this is how
you plan to resolve
the fate of the world's most
important economic resource?
One minute into Centipede,
the ice broke.
It has to be Joust!
still holds the world record
on the 2600 port of that game.
Maybe we just need
to beat his high score.
Pitfall! One of the only 2600
games that still hasn't ended.
And how about
those Swordquest games?
Yes!
The Swordquest games.
They were created for a contest
Atari held with real...
how are we doin'?
To be honest, I think I need
physical therapy because it's not...
Um, as you wish.
Ah...
How does it work?
Has it got, like,
a remote or is there a button or something?
it's a level-99 magic artifact,
not one of your drones,
so it is activated by a magic spell.
Would you care
to do the honors?
That was a corporate decision.
It was not personal.
You're gonna tell me
exactly which rig she's in
Yeah, that seems appropriate.
Where's the rig?
We're in his account.
We grabbed him in transit just as
he was logging out of the OASIS,
So, you basically
just remotely hacked his rig.
A fixed rig is easy to locate, hard to hack.
Unless he's stupid enough to
leave his password lying around.
Loyalty center, I'm in.
I'm tapped directly
into your audio feed.
We got his password,
hacked rig.
And there's more,
they just put a force field
around Castle.
I heard one of the guards calling it
and the only way to take it
down is from the inside.
She's right.
Level-99 artifact,
creates a magic-resistant,
impenetrable barrier.
No way through it.
All right, so I'm looking
at a diagram of your rig.
Okay, inside the panel,
there's a lever.
Grab it with your right hand
and slide it to the left.
That should release you.
It worked. It worked, I'm out.
Loyalty pod 41-F,
you are on an authorized
break for 10 minutes.
Pod 41-F, you are
on 10-minute break.
Proceed to break area.
It's in the IOI war room,
two levels above where you are now.
You need to raise an army.
I'm gonna take down
that shield.
Wait, Arty, wait!
You gotta get out of there!
This isn't real,
you're tapping my feed.
they've hacked my rig.
They're after the girl.
Pod 41-F,
you have exceeded your break time.
Report to security
So, she just walks out of here,
how does that happen?
They're smart. They knew
what they were doing.
But we know they're in Columbus.
And now, all five of them are together.
Wait. Wait, we know what?
How do we know?
We have the make and model of the van.
We'll spot them.
"We'll spot them"?
That sounds like a great
inscription for our tombstones.
Why didn't you tell me
this earlier?
It wasn't relevant yet.
We need to know.
We need to find them!
They're kids,
Man the hell up!
Do your job, and I'll do mine,
unless you wanna take this
and go after them yourself.
The Complete Nancy Drew,
Kegel Exercises for...
Bingo. Okay.
"Congratulations,
you are the proud owner,
"a 99th level magic artifact.
"Read these instructions before deploying.
To turn orb on, off."
Off! Yes, off.
"Utter spell
within 10 feet of orb."
I'm here talking to all of you now
because our future's being threatened
by people who will stop at
nothing to win this contest.
Some of you already know this,
and you've lost much more than
just your avatars or your weapons.
I only came here to escape the
shitty hand that life dealt me.
I found a cause.
And yes, I know
it's kind of a groaner, but...
And I don't wanna lose that
to this colossal douchebag,
He thinks that we're all too
distracted to even notice...
put up a fight.
This is going out live!
The only thing
let this guy do...
- ...was get him a cup of coffee.
And now, we're supposed
to hand him the OASIS?
Oh, man.
Come on, come on.
Give me this thing.
Left arm.
- Left arm!
- Sir.
No, I need the left arm.
No, I don't care if...
I want it on.
He thinks that we won't
even put up a fight!
gunter
clans in the gold mines of Gygax.
Activate the Iron Giant.
In the name of James himself,
Squadron 14, armor up,
you're in the lead.
One minute into Swordquest,
the ice broke.
Well, all three Swordquests.
Dark Cavern, Laser Blast.
It's Adventure.
Released in 1979,
for the 2600,
Adventure was created by
Warren Robinett,
who was the first video game designer
ever to hide his name. In fact...
I'd say about ten...
Yeah, about 10 million years,
so we should be fine.
The Sixers are in the final challenge.
It's an Atari 2600.
No, no, no.
You gotta get out of there.
Created!
He was the first designer to
ever hide an Easter egg in...
We're looking for a USPS truck,
Ohio plates,
a drone spitter, 2036 model.
When are you
getting into this fight?
I'm out. Inventory's empty.
Last clip for me.
Anti-personnel
ordinance cannon!
Railgun!
fucking Chucky!
Mechagodzilla!
Get to the bridge.
Go now, he's distracted.
He's only got 30 seconds
Hang on!
we've got this.
You need to log out.
If the game is Adventure,
why haven't they won yet?
Get it together, Sixer.
Back to respawn.
Holy hand grenade!
How much did that cost?
Less than
it's gonna cost them.
Sir, the gunters
are approaching the challenge.
Remember
announcement.
The keys are invisible,
and they're hidden in a dark room
that's at the center
of a maze.
Well, there's a secret in Adventure,
and you don't find it by winning.
You find it by wandering
around in a dark room.
Until you get
to the invisible dot.
It's pretty easy
if you know what you're doing.
Let me finish it for you.
Why the hell
would I ever do that?
Dude!
That's the Cataclyst.
I'd just as soon never set
foot in the OASIS again,
let alone have to deal
with any of this absurdity.
But I know how important
competition is to you, so...
Well, that's fine.
Three easy steps. One.
Wait, I thought you were bluffing.
You know that kills all of us, right?
I've got 10 years' worth
of shit inside of me.
I'm not goin' out like that.
That's a camper move.
You don't even know
how to activate an orb.
Hadouken!
Live feed
in all OASIS channels.
's letting everyone
watch the end of the contest.
God damn it,
we tried Adventure.
No, we tried to win it.
But the hidden room isn't
at the end of the game.
You've gotta go straight to the
invisible dot at the start.
doesn't know what planet she's on?
Toshiro.
Yeah, I know. Not what
you were expecting,
Yeah, I wasn't expecting
a late '30s-model postal van.
Wait, I thought the Cataclyst went off.
How are you still playing?
Ninjas
I've got a drone on their tail.
I'm close.
Send me coordinates.
Maybe you should
leave this to me,
What's goin' on out there?
- The game is over for them.
- What are they watching?
He wanted people to know
who was behind it.
That's why he created
the first digital Easter egg
and to find it,
you didn't even have to win.
You just had to blindly play,
searching around
in rooms for an invisible dot.
You took the dot
back to the main screen
and that's when you found the first
Easter egg ever put in a video game.
The creator's name.
What's going on, man?
I can't see shit.
just got the Crystal Key!
what the hell's going on?
Just practicing Mario Kart.
What do you think?
IOI's trying to kill us, man!
Everyone watching,
if you're in the Columbus stacks,
real-world,
and we're gonna need your help.
head for the stacks!
Okay, hold on!
Stick the key in,
how hard is it?
Now, you just sign these papers,
and the OASIS is yours.
You will be
its sole proprietor.
That ain't so bad, is it?
I'm gonna need a second.
sign over his shares
in Gregarious.
This is where you grew up.
Oh, that's just me
a long time ago.
I like to have him around
from time to time.
Hey, I have
to show you something.
This, uh... Come on.
This is the button.
If you push it,
the whole simulation shuts down
and a tapeworm program will
erase all of the backup servers.
So you now have the power
to turn the OASIS off forever.
Do you understand?
Yeah,
try not to accidentally erase
the whole of the OASIS
on your first day.
The stacks are straight ahead!
Well, I expect you have to go.
I know I do.
So, now is the time for you
to receive your prize
because you won
all three keys.
Once you take this egg,
the game will be over.
The egg, the egg...
We know what you did here.
You turn around and walk out
of here while you still can.
I created the OASIS
because I never felt at home
in the real world.
I just didn't know how to
connect with the people there.
I was afraid
for all of my life.
Right up until the day
I knew my life was ending.
Now, that... That was when
I realized that,
as terrifying and painful
as reality can be,
it's also the only place
Hooray.
Hold it!
Hands on your head.
You're not an avatar, are you?
Now, there are some people out here
that would very much like to meet you.
Wow, this is incredible.
It's an honor to meet you,
Og, but I...
We need you to make a statement
about the clip you sent in
confession.
What? I record everything
in my workshop.
Who are you guys?
The people you need right now, lawyers.
From Gregarious Games.
I'm splitting it with my clan.
We're gonna
run things together.
how'd you get here so fast?
I flew from the stars
on my magic sleigh.
Everyone's been watching.
Of course, I've been watching
a little closer than most.
Jim told me nothing
about the contest,
so there was no rule about me
losing a bet to a smart kid.
Not that you needed my help.
You figured out that
on your own.
You were the Rosebud.
Oh. Well, look who it is.
It's my heroes, the High Five.
and the first thing we did
was sign to
a non-exclusive consultancy.
The salary, per his demand,
was 25 cents. One quarter.
With his guidance,
our second move was to ban
any loyalty centers
from accessing the OASIS.
The third thing we did
wasn't as popular.
I know, it sounds
like a weird move,
but people need to spend
more time in the real world.